researchresults.com 2019-05-20

# Privacy Act Statement - Research Results

### Our Privacy Commitments

Research Results Inc. respects the privacy of every panel member. This privacy statement outlines the information Research Results Inc. will collect and how we will use that information and how you can request that we delete or update your personal information.

This privacy statement is intended to describe some of the ways that we implement our Information Privacy Guiding Principles in connection with our online survey activities. We’ve developed this privacy statement from industry guidelines and standards, and local, national, and international laws and requirements. All privacy practices and methods described in this statement apply only insofar as permitted by the applicable standards, laws and requirements. In addition, as a member of the Council of American Survey Research Organizations (CASRO), the professional trade association of survey research companies, Research Results Inc. adheres to the mandated CASRO Code of Standards and Ethics for Survey Research. You may visit CASRO, and view the CASRO Code, at www.casro.org.

### Information Collected and How We Use It

#### What We Collect

**Personal and Demographic Information**  
During the Research Results Inc. recruitment process, we may collect personal information such as your name, address, and the ages of members of your household (“Personal Information”). In addition, Research Results Inc. frequently asks panel members for characteristics (such as health problems or consumer habits), attributes and demographic information (such as age, income, gender) (collectively, Demographic Information).

You are in control of the Personal Information and Demographic Information that you provide to Research Results Inc. We rely on you to provide updates to your Personal Information and Demographic Information. You can:

**Ask for a copy of your Personal Information or Demographic Information**  
Ask for your Personal Information or Demographic Information to be corrected or updated  
Ask us to remove your Personal Information or Demographic Information from your records

To do this, please contact us using the links provided later in this statement. Research Results Inc. will use reasonable efforts to provide the requested information to you.

**Operating Information**  
Research Results Inc. may, in the course of interacting with panel members, gather other types of information from panel members (“Operating Information”). For example, as a Research Results Inc. Panel Member, you will receive surveys from Research Results Inc. on a regular basis. These surveys will ask questions about your interests, needs, and attitudes. We will receive your responses to these surveys. Similarly, if we offer other features, services, or programs in which you explicitly agree to participate, then Research Results Inc. will receive information from those features, services, or programs.

#### How We Use Your Information:

**Personal and Demographic Information**  
Personal Information may be used to set up email accounts for each household member who is 13 years of age or older, to communicate with you and your household members, and to assist you with questions that you may have about the Research Results Inc. panel. It may also be used for panel recruitment, contest entry processing or delivery of free gifts to members of the Research Results Inc. panel. Personal Information concerning location or address is also used to ensure that our panel accuracy represents the country’s population as a whole.

Panel members are asked for Demographic Information in order to pre-qualify members or households for surveys that target specific groups. We also use this information to ensure that our panel accurately represents the country’s population as a whole.

Research Results Inc. uses Personal Information and Demographic Information solely in the conduct of its research business. Personal Information or Demographic Information may be combined with Information collected about you by research Results Inc. or third parties with your express permission, with information that is collected about you from public records, or with information that Research Results Inc. may acquire from third parties that have a legal right to provide such information to Research Results Inc.

**Operating Information**  
Research Results Inc. uses Operating Information solely in the conduct of its research business. As is the case with Personal Information and Demographic Information, Operating Information may be combined with information collected about you by third parties with your express permission, with information that is collected about you from public records, or with information that Research Results Inc. may acquire from third parties that have a legal right to provide such information to Research Results Inc.

### Data Sharing and Transfer

#### How We Share Information

Personal Information regarding Panel Members will never be shared with any third parties without your express permission, except that we may disclose your information if we believe we are required to do so by law, if we need to do so to protect someone’s safety or our rights or property, or in order to comply with this policy or other policies that may be applicable. In addition, occasionally Research Results Inc. will share contact information, such as name and address, with third parties with whom we have partnered to provide specific services to Research Results Inc., or services on behalf of Research Results Inc., such as panel recruitment, contest entry processing or delivery of free gifts to Research Results Inc. Panel Members. These partners have agreed not to share or resell this data and they are contractually obligated not to use any personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services unless you enter into a relationship with them that would directly allow them to do so.

Research Results Inc. collects and shares Demographic Information and Operating Information with its research clients in an anonymous form. Our research clients will never receive Personal Information or Panel Members, nor will they be able to identify Panel Members, without your express permission.

**Data Transfers**  
Your Personal Information, Demographic Information, and Operating Information will generally be stored in our Research Results Inc. databases, which are located in the United States. For easier processing of e-mail communications, contests, sweepstakes, or other marketing purposes, however, your Personal Information, Demographic Information, or Operating Information may be sent, usually on a temporary basis, to trusted partner companies. Research Results Inc. data protection standards are the same, regardless of where your information is stored.

**Children’s Privacy**  
Research Results Inc. believes that it’s especially important to protect children’s privacy online. We comply with all applicable national and international children’s privacy regulations.

Specifically, Research Results Inc. complies with the Children’s Online Privacy Act of 1998. We do not permit children under the age of 13 to become panel members. We do not collect any Personal Information from children under 13 years of age.

If a panel member has provided us with Personal Information about a child in the panel member’s household who is under the age of 13, a parent or guardian of that child may contact us at the email address or mailing address listed at the bottom of this Privacy Statement if he or she would like this information deleted from our records. We will use reasonable efforts to delete the child’s information from our databases.

If you would like to contact us about your child’s Personal Information or find out how you can have your child’s Personal Information removed from our databases, please see the “Access To Your Information and Complaints” section later in this document.

**Data Security and Responsibility**  
Research Results Inc. is committed to keeping the data you provide us secure and will take reasonable precautions to protect your Personal Information from loss, misuse or alteration. Vendors, contractors, or partners of Research Results Inc. who have access to your Personal Information in Connection with providing service for Research Results Inc. are contractually required to keep the information confidential and are not permitted to use this information for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for Research Results Inc.

Research Results Inc. also safeguards Personal Information, Demographic Information, and Operating Information from unauthorized access. Most Operating Information is maintained in databases that are separate from those containing Personal Information and Demographic Information. Only authorized Research Results Inc. employees or agents carrying out permitted business functions are allowed to access these databases.

### Access to Your Information and Complaints

**Accessing, Correcting, Updating and Preventing the Use of Your Personal Information or Demographic Information**  
If you have submitted Personal or Demographic Information to Research Results Inc. through the Research Results Inc. Panel, or otherwise, or if someone else has otherwise submitted your Personal or Demographic Information to Research Results Inc. you can:  
Access, correct, update your Personal or Demographic Information, by emailing your request to: info@researchresults.com, with “privacy” in the subject line or by sending us a letter to the address below. Research Results Inc. will use reasonable efforts to supply you with the information that your requested to access and correct any factual inaccuracies in this information

Prevent further use of your Personal or Demographic Information by emailing your request to: info@researchresults.com, with “privacy” in the subject line or by sending us a letter to the address below. Research Results Inc. will use reasonable efforts to prevent further use of your Personal or Demographic Information in our files.

**Complaints**  
Research Results Inc. is committed to working with consumers to obtain a fair and rapid resolution of any complaints or disputes about privacy. Please send us your questions or comments regarding our privacy practices by emailing us at: info@researchresults.com, with “privacy” in the subject line or send us a letter to:  
Privacy Compliance Coordinator  
Research Results Inc.  
915 South Street  
Fitchburg, MA 01420

**Opting Out**  
At any time you may discontinue your participation in the Research Results Inc Panel by sending us an email (info@researchresults.com, with “privacy” in the subject line) or by calling 978-345-5510. Parents or legal guardians of any member of the Research Results Inc. Panel who is under the age of eighteen may discontinue the participation of such child in the same manner. Please note that opting out of the Research Results Inc. Panel will not automatically cause us to delete Personal, Demographic, or Operating Information about you (or your child) that we have previously collected. We will do so, however, at your request, as set forth above.

**Other Sites**  
Research Results Inc. is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other Web sites. We recommend that you carefully read the privacy policies of each site that you visit.

### Contact Us

You may contact us at:  
Research Results Inc.  
915 South Street  
Fitchburg, MA 01420  
978-345-5510  
info@researchresults.com, (with “privacy” in the subject line)

### Your Acceptance of Our Privacy Practices

By agreeing to become a Research Results Inc. panel member or participating in a Research Results Inc.’s service or program, you signify your acceptance of the terms and conditions of this Privacy Statement. Research Results Inc. may make changes to this Privacy Statement from time to time. We will post changes to our Privacy Statement on the Research Results Inc Panel Member Web Site. In addition, we will alert you to significant changes to this Privacy Statement by providing you with written, electronic, or other notice from Research Results Inc.
